# ABHISHEK DAREKAR

# SUMMARY

Reliable Business Professional with 4+ years experience in Transportation and Logistics sector seeking career transition into Data Science. Proficiency of platforms for programming, data analysis, visualizations, statistics and machine learning. Ready to combine tireless hunger for new skills with desire to exploit cutting-edge data science technology.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**DATA ANALYSIS** Excel, Google Sheets **PROGRAMMING** Python, R, Java

DATABASEMySQL, BigQuery, SQLServer, MongoDBDATA VISUALIZATIONTableau, Matplotlib, Seaborn, ggplot2

MACHINE LEARNING Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras

**DEPLOYMENT** AWS, GCP, Heroku

OTHER MLflow, Pyspark, Docker, git

# CERTIFICATIONS

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, by Coursera

Complete Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp, by Udemy

Jan. 2022

Mar. 2022

# **PROJECTS**

Predicting heart disease using Logistic Regression, K-Nearest Neighbours Classifier and Random Forest Classifier deployed on AWS EC2 using flask API containerized in Docker

Predicting the Sale Price of Bulldozers using **RandomForestRegressor**, managed different hyperparameters using **MLflow** and deployed over **Heroku** using **Jupyter Notebook** 

End-to-End Multi-Class Dog Breeds Image Classifier using **TensorFlow 2.x** and **TensorFlow Hub** trained on **imagenet/mobilenet\_v2\_130\_224/classification** model in **Google Colab** 

Implemented a creative Visualization Dashboard on Real-Time Covid-19 data using Tableau

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Darekar Transport and Logistics Services, Administrator, Santacruz, Mumbai

July 2018 - Jan. 2022

- Supervised and maintained sales data, weekly reports in Excel for tracking business transactions
- Developed a Customer Feedback Portal using J2EE on Tomcat server and MySQL system
- Collaborated with Transport teams for timely completion of assigned cargo operations
- Diversified services into Nursery sector generating revenue more than 80% within 3 years

#### Verchaska Infotech Pvt Ltd, Junior Java Developer, Vashi, Navi Mumbai

Nov. 2017 - July 2018

- Designed highly scalable, testable code with 96% positive feedback from mentors
- Analyzed and maintained 2 existing software applications
- Helped with writing and optimizing SQL queries for faster performance

# **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor Of Engineering (Computer) from Mumbai University

2014 - 2017